scienceofpain.com 2019-06-17

# Bayer Consumer Care Products

  |  |  | 

---|---  
  
Bayer is aware that the security of your private information from the use of our websites, mobile apps or other online services (“Website”) is an important concern. We take the protection of your personal data very seriously. Therefore we would like you to know what data we maintain and what data we discard. With this privacy statement, we would like to inform you about our security measures.

## Collection of Data

You can use many features of our Website without disclosing your personal data. You are not required to provide personal data as a condition of using our Website, except as may be necessary to provide you a product or service at your request; these products or services may include some of our apps or online services, such as those providing premium content or exclusive offers. When you use our Website, certain data may be stored for various purposes, including security, site functionality, analytics and marketing purposes. This data may include the name of your internet service provider, the website that you used to link to our Website, the websites that you visit from our Website and your IP-Address or device identifier. This data could possibly lead to your identification, but we do not use it to do so or combine it with personal data without your consent. We do use the data from time to time for statistical purposes, but maintain the anonymity of each individual user so that the person cannot be identified. If you elect to participate in certain analytics, communications and marketing programs, including those operated or run by third parties, we may also enhance personal data by obtaining or merging personal data with technical, cookie or other data we collect or that we receive from third parties; we would use this enhanced data to create a more complete profile for a more customized user experience. In cases when personal data is provided to others to provide you products or services you have requested, or for other purposes you have authorized, we rely on technical and organizational means to assure that applicable data security regulations are followed. If you register or log into your account through a third-party social networking service then we may receive certain information associated with your account with that social networking service, such as your name and email address. You may have the ability to control what information is shared from these third-party social networking services by adjusting the privacy settings on those services. 

## Collection and processing of personal data

We collect personal data only when you provide it to us, through registration, completion of forms or e-mails, as part of an order for products or services, inquiries or requests about materials being ordered and similar situations in which you have chosen to provide the information to us. This also includes information that we receive when you register or log into your account through a third-party social networking service.

In addition, we use the services of a third-party social listening platform that compiles publicly accessible content on the internet in order to create aggregate reports that allow us to better understand our brand categories and more effectively market our products. This publicly accessible content may include personal data, such as your name or username in connection with a social media profile. To the extent we obtain any such data, we will maintain it in accordance with this privacy statement, and use it only for the purposes described in this privacy statement.

The personal data you disclose to us remains at our company and/or with data processors or servers acting on our behalf and responsible to us. We may disclose the personal data we collect to third party service providers in connection with services that they perform for us, such as running and fulfilling promotions, conducting surveys, and e-mail and direct mail delivery services. Your personal data will not otherwise be passed on by us or by our agents for use by third parties in any form whatsoever, unless we have obtained your consent, are legally required to do so such as to comply with law or a legal request such as a subpoena, to protect the company’s rights, property or interests, or in the event of a sale of assets or other corporate restructuring.

We will retain control of and responsibility for the use of any personal data you disclose to us. Some of this data may be stored or processed at computers located in other jurisdictions whose data protection laws may differ from the jurisdiction in which you live. In such cases, we will ensure that appropriate protections are in place to require the data processor in that country to maintain protections on the data that are equivalent to those that apply in the country in which you live. 

## Purposes of Use

The personal data we collect will only be used for the purpose of supplying you with the requested products or services or for other purposes for which you have given your consent, except where otherwise provided by law.

## Right of Access and Correction

You have the right to review and amend any personal data in your account profile and, where applicable, personal account preferences, stored in our system if you believe it may be out of date or incorrect. Just contact the Head of Data Privacy or the Director of Data Privacy – U.S. at the address below, or where applicable, log in to your account to update your information and/or preferences. 

## Right of Cancellation

You have the right at any time to withdraw your consent to the use of your personal data in the future. Again, just send an e-mail to the address given in the imprint or contact the Head of Data Privacy or the Director of Data Privacy – U.S. at the address below. Where applicable, you may also log in to your account to update your preferences, which may include revoking consent to certain communication outreach and marketing uses. 

## Data Retention

We retain personal data for as long as necessary consistent with the purposes of use and in a manner consistent with our records management policies or as otherwise required by law (e.g., in connection with pending litigation).

## Use of Cookies and other Tracking Technologies

This website uses so-called “Cookies.” Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard drive through the visitor's local browser cache. Using such cookies it is possible to recognize the visitor's browser in order to optimize the website and simplify its use. Data collected via cookies will not be used to determine the personal identity of the website visitor.

Because an industry-standard Do-Not-Track protocol is not yet established, Bayer’s information collection and disclosure practices and the choices it offers to consumers will continue to operate as described in this privacy statement regardless of a “do not track” choice made by the consumer.

Most browsers are set-up to accept Cookies automatically. In addition, you can deactivate the storing of cookies or adjust your browser to inform you before the Cookie is stored on your computer. In the case of third-party cookies for interest-based advertising, you can opt out of receiving interest-based ads for web properties [here](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN) (Digital Advertising Alliance’s WebChoices) or for mobile apps [here](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices) (Digital Advertising Alliance’s AppChoices).

We use cookies for two main purposes: (1) cookies to facilitate technical aspects or special features on our site, without which the functionality of our website would be reduced, and (2) cookies for analytics and marketing purposes. Technical cookies aid site functionality and facilitate navigation and settings, including anonymous identification of a session (website visit), language preferences, mobile or desktop site version settings, or shopping cart sessions. The lifespan of these cookies range from deletion at the end of a browser session to up to 60 days for preference settings, and some cookies may persist for up to one year.

The data collected via a cookie may be used to gather statistical information or technical information like day and time of your visit as well as device type or browser used to access our site. We also collect basic user information like pages visited and user preferences that can be used to improve future web experiences when you return to one of the Websites. The preference data we collect could include information like region, language or user name to be able to provide you a more personalized experience and deliver content more relevant to your interests. While we do leverage the information we collect in aggregate to deliver more relevant advertisements and offers to you on other third party websites as you navigate the Internet, we do not share your personal data with any third party vendor or website owner for their own marketing purposes. We may also include a cookie on promotional offers/communications (email) to be able to measure performance and deliver more relevant offers/content based on preferences.

Below is a classification of the cookies we leverage across Bayer web properties to collect and manage data. This could vary from site to site but this is a full list.

Cookie: | Analytics  
---|---  
Collection Point: | Various data gathered from each page of web experience to measure and report  
Classification: | Bayer and 3rd Party  
Purpose: | Bayer Websites are tagged with analytics cookies to collect information about how visitors use our website and we leverage this information to make your experience more relevant based on your interest.   
Cookie:  | Media Advertising  
---|---  
Collection Point: | First impression of Bayer Media to optimize display/video/mobile advertising.  
Classification: | 3rd Party  
Purpose: | Bayer leverages third party cookies to collect information related to media & site engagement and use this information to deliver relevant ads based on user interest & preferences.  
Cookie:  | Interest-Based Advertising  
---|---  
Collection Point: | On any or all pages of the Bayer Websites to deliver targeted media ads on 3rd party sites  
Classification:  | 3rd Party   
Purpose:  | Bayer Websites allow third parties to serve cookies for purposes of delivering interest-based media ads when users engage with 3rd party websites.  
Cookie:  | 3rd Party Engagement Tools  
---|---  
Collection Point: | On specific pages of web experience to support the integration of engagement tools.  
Classification: | 3rd Party  
Purpose: | To provide the user with a seamless user experience when engaging with tools like coupon, where to buy and buy online, ratings & reviews, and exit surveys.  
Cookie:  | Bayer Web Experience  
---|---  
Collection Point: | The first page of visit and across web experience to collect and manage preferences.  
Classification: | Bayer  
Purpose: | To collect and save user preferences to be able to optimize user experience including but not limited to any registration form complete and/or other preference related selections.  
Cookie: | Social Integration  
---|---  
Collection Point:  | The first page that the user visits and any page where content is shared   
Classification:  | Bayer and 3rd Party   
Purpose:  | When visiting a Bayer website we provide the capability that allows a visitor to share specific web pages & content via Facebook, Twitter, email and other means. This function uses a cookie to collect anonymous information when you visit and share our content.   
  
## Analytics and Marketing

Through the use of cookies and other technologies described above, we, and our third party service providers on our behalf, may analyze how you use our website to develop insights to optimize website use and improve personalized site experiences, communications and marketing. Our analytics, for marketing and other purposes, is based on technical or other anonymous or aggregate information. You may delete or opt-out of this anonymous tracking and analysis at any time by altering your cookie settings and/or deleting cookies. More information on these opt-outs is provided below. 

We may also use personal data for analytics and marketing purposes, including analyzing your use of our website and your activity on other Websites, including coupon redemption, with your express consent. If you chose to create an account on our site, you may elect to participate in certain analytics, communications and marketing programs, including coupon programs and other special offers. If you opt-in, we may collect such personal data from you as demographic, contact and preference information from your account profile, as well as from your interactions on the site, such as through quiz responses or other interactive features. This information could include Personal Data such as name, address, email or other data that could be used to identify you as an individual. We may also enhance or merge this data with the cookie data we collect or possibly merge data from third parties to create a more complete profile for a more customized user experience. This information would be stored in a secure database within the Bayer environment and would not be shared with any third party without your prior consent. You may control your preferences directly on your account and revoke consent to future participation in these analytics or marketing programs at any time.

**_Google Analytics._** Our website uses third party service providers, including Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States (“ ** _Google_** ”).

Bayer and our service providers will analyze your use of our website on our behalf. To this purpose, we use, among others, the Cookies described in above. The information collected within the Google Analytics platform in connection with your use of our website (e.g. the referring URL, which of our webpages you visit, your browser type, your language settings, your operating system, your screen resolution) will be transmitted to a server of Google in the U.S., where it will be stored and analyzed; the respective results will then be made available to us in an anonymized form. In this process, your usage data will not be connected to your full IP address. We have activated on our website the IP anonymizing function offered by Google, so that the last 8 digits (type IPv4) or the last 80 bits (type IPv6) of your IP address are deleted. 

You may withdraw your consent to the use of web analysis at any time either by downloading and installing a [Browser Plugin](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB) offered by Google or by configuring your browser to delete and reject cookies. Both options will prevent the use of web analysis only if you use the browser on which you installed the plugin.

For further information on Google Analytics please refer to the [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html), the [Google Analytics security and privacy principles](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en), and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en-GB/policies/privacy/).

**_Text Message Marketing Communications_**. From time to time, Bayer may engage in text message marketing campaigns, such as for text-based coupons or promotional materials. Bayer shall only send you text messages with your prior express consent at the phone number that you have provided to participate in the text message marketing campaign. You may opt-out of ongoing or subscription texts at any time by responding to the opt-out instructions in such texts. Please note that if you opt-out of future text messages, this opt-out list is separate from our email preferences and opt-out lists.

## Security

Bayer uses technical and organizational security precautions to protect your data from manipulation, loss, destruction or access by unauthorized persons. Any personal data that is provided to Bayer by you will be encrypted in transit to prevent its possible misuse by third parties. Our security procedures are continuously revised based on new technological developments. Although we strive to keep your personal information secure, no security measures are absolute. Use caution when transmitting personal information over the Internet. 

## Social Media

Bayer uses social media accounts (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Pinterest and Instagram) to engage with the public. Through our social media engagement we are able to build online awareness about our company and our products, respond to messages through the comment-, message-, or chat- functions, collect aggregated information about interactions with our content on or through social media, analyze trends, identify and profile brand advocates and key influencers. We also use social media listening services as described above. When you engage with us through our social media channels, the platform providers will also process information about you. For further information, please consult the privacy policy of the platform provider.

## Security

Bayer uses technical and organizational security precautions to protect your data from manipulation, loss, destruction or access by unauthorized persons. Any personal data that is provided to Bayer by you will be encrypted in transit to prevent its possible misuse by third parties. Our security procedures are continuously revised based on new technological developments. Although we strive to keep your personal data secure, no security measures are absolute. Use caution when transmitting personal data over the Internet. 

## Children

In light of the importance of protecting children's privacy, we do not collect, process or use on our website any information relating to an individual whom we know to be under 13 years old without the prior, verifiable consent of his or her legal representative. Such legal representative has the right, upon request, to view the information provided by the child and/or to require that it be deleted.

## Contacts

If you have any problems, questions, or ideas, please contact:

Bayer U.S. LLC  
Director of Data Privacy – U.S.  
100 Bayer Road  
Pittsburgh, PA 15205  

The constant development of the internet requires occasional adjustments to our privacy statement. We retain the right to make changes when necessary, and will communicate any updates promptly on this page. Please check back periodically.

Last updated April 24, 2019
